PIERRE ANDRÉ LOWENSTEIN FULL STACK WEB DEVELOPER | UI/UX DESIGNER

Los Angeles, CA | (310) 876-2856 | <u>coder@pierreandrelowenstein.com</u> <u>linkedin.com/in/palowenstein</u> | <u>github.com/palowenstein</u> | <u>pierreandrelowenstein.com</u>

Bi-national, solution-oriented professional with extensive experience in digital media, post-production, web development. Expertise includes full-stack software engineering, project management, digital delivery and post-production while overseeing business processes and communications. Possesses a successful track record of leading diverse teams and improving operational workflows while promoting a positive culture in fast-paced work environments.

SKILLS

Core Competencies: Full Stack Web Dev, UI/UX Design, WCD / Digital Assets Creation, SEO.

Web Development Competencies:

Languages: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, PHP, React, JSX (React/Redux).

Environments / Frameworks: Node, React, Redux, Express, SQL, MySQL/Sequelize, MongoDB/Mongoose, JSON, Postman, Webpack, RESTful APIs, Object-Oriented Programming (OOP), Object-Relational Mapping (ORM), Model-View-Controller (MVC), MERN/MEVN Solution Stack, Git, GitHub, CMS: Wordpress/GRAV, Google Analytics, YoastSEO.

PROJECTS

Athleta (GAP, Inc.) | https://athleta.gap.com/

GAP's upcoming female exclusive clothing brand is launching its Canada local subsidiary, and localized web site.

- Coded front-end merchandise pages, in-sort marketing (ISM), informational pages based on vouched design requirements.
- Transited between producers, designers, WCD members, localization team as to guarantee 100% authenticity in delivery.
- ~ JSON, JSX, REACT, XHTML/CSS, Photoshop, Illustrator, Smart Sheet, MS Teams (remote team interaction).

Insight RX | http://sheltered-shelf-78967.herokuapp.com/

Health Care Start-Up needs an event creation / management tool built in React for its internal event capture service (HERO).

- Front End Designer: Built a front-end User Interface (UI) to navigate between components.
- Component Creator: Date Component interacting with API events data retrieval via hook, props and state transfer (Redux).
- ~ JS, Node.js, React.js, Redux, Express.js, Redis cache, auth0, JSON, Axios, Trie, Lodash, Echarts, dotenv, Postman.

Honda Automobiles | https://honda-zipcode.herokuapp.com/

Auto Company needs a pure vanilla JavaScript ZIP code locator for its web

- Created a server-side API component that would display Honda service centers within a zip code radius.
- Recreated Honda's web site look & feel from scratch for component inclusion.
- ~ Asynchronous JS, async/await, fetch, JSON, HTTP GET and POST requests.

Michelson Patents | https://michelsonpatents.com

Inventor Extraordinaire Gary K. Michelson requires a dynamically maintained patents web site.

- Oversaw / Created a database-centric website of all patents filed by Dr. Michelson (340 domestic, 1000+ international).
- Created a component that maintains Dr. Michelson's patents directory in real-time based on USPTO's API.
- ~ Wordpress CMS, PHP, HTML/CSS, AJAX Get / Post Requests, Photoshop, Illustrator.

Michelson Medical Research Foundation | https://michelsonmedical.org

Non-Profit Medical Foundation requires an interactive, SEO driven web site to display initiatives and interact with beneficiaries.

- Project Manager / Coded / Designed front end / back end of site, authored look & feel based on customer's requirements.
- Managed team of medical writers, graphic designers, social media managers, videographers throughout length of project.
- ~ Wordpress CMS, PHP, HTML/CSS, Yoast SEO, Photoshop, Illustrator, Final Cut Pro, Media Composer, Digital Performer.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

GAP, Inc. — Front-End Web Developer, Athleta WCD Team

San Francisco, NY — 05/2021 – 09/2021

- Collaborated with Athleta's design, producing teams in adapting InVision mock-ups and incorporating weekly updated visual assets into fully functional REACT web pages.
- Created JSON code to solve technical challenges associated with the display layout of new marketing material.
- Coded parts of Athleta's Canadian bilingual launch, backported the more recent Canada code onto the US site.

Sample Logic — *UI/UX Consultant, Presets Author*

New York City, NY — 01/2021 – 04/2021

- Consulted with Sample Logic to assist on Animation Station, their first Digital Audio Workstation (DAW) MIDI plug-in.
- Contributed weekly engineering, UI/UX reports from Pre-Alpha stage to Release Candidate Stage.
- Created a series of software presets shipped with the live release.

Insight RX — Front-End Web Developer, Component Coder

San Francisco, CA — 05/2020 – 09/2020

- Built a front-end User Interface (UI) for HERO, InsightRX's in-house event registration application.
- Created a Date Component interacting with API events data retrieval via hook, props and state transfer.
- Contributed concept demonstration content to weekly / bi-weekly SCRUM, Sprint meetings.
- Worked directly with Insight RX's director of engineering and Insight RX's senior software engineer.

Honda Automobiles — Front-End Web Developer, UI Designer

Torrance, CA - 04/2020 - 05/2020

- Reverse-engineered Honda Automobiles' web site look and feel to incorporate a zip code component.
- Helped create a server-side API component that would display Honda service centers within a zip code radius.

Karlin Asset Management — Front-End Web Developer, Senior Digital Producer Los Angeles, CA — 03/2014 – 04/2019

- Managed the media presence of a high net worth principal, three foundations; \$150K annual budget.
- Engineered customized CMS/SEO driven web sites, wrote, curated news articles, biographical, general content.
- Led coverage detailing philanthropic investments of MMRF. Maintained relationships with MMRF Beneficiaries such as: University of Southern California, Wharton School of Business, SABIN Vaccine Institute, University of Washington.
- Produced interviews / featurettes covering MMRF initiatives: USC Michelson Center for Convergent Bioscience, Michelson Prizes, Future of Vaccine Development Conference, SABIN Vaccine Institute, USC Leonard Davis School of Gerontology incl. well-known fasting specialist Valter Longo, lifespan visionary Mei-Lee Ney.
- Wrote informational sections devoted to the Medtronic vs. Karlin Technology trial (\$1.35B settlement) the America Invents Act signed by President Obama, Dr. Michelson's public image as an inventor, patent holder, and IP educator.
- Achieved 50% of Google's first page for Dr. Gary Michelson (5 out of 10 rankings).

Calmwater Capital — Web Architect

Los Angeles, CA — 02/2017 – 04/2019

- Delivered brand new web architecture to Co-Founder, Senior Portfolio Manager of Calmwater Capital Management.
- Restructured web management of existing site and optimized its SEO to increase user traffic and lead generation.

Soundtrack Specialist Inc. — Senior Digital Producer

Venice, CA — 09/2001 – Present

- Delivered scores for features, shorts, commercials; which aired on various international online platforms.
- Orchestrated major motion picture, X2: X-Men United ending sequence "Dark Phoenix Reveal".
- Assisted film composers including CLIFF EIDELMAN (Star Trek VI, He's Just Not That Into You, Big Miracle).
- Documented the creative process behind the music of The Simpsons (video documentary).
- Credits include: Nighthawk, In Vitro, Bushido, Put It Away, The Last Drive, The Road, o/One, Black Berry (Ad).
- Interviewed European and Hollywood based film composers active in the film industry (SFX Magazine).

EDUCATION

Certificate in Full Stack Web Development. UCLA Extension.

Bachelor of Arts in Film Scoring and minor in Orchestra Conducting. Berklee College of Music.

Bachelor of Arts in Jazz Studies and minor in Jazz Piano. American School of Modern Music.